# Glen Correia

| (682)-583-9372 | gpc0331@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/glencorrreia/ | https://github.com/glencorrreia/ |

### **Professional Summary**

Adventurous and **Tech Explorer** software engineer with over **3 years** of hands-on experience navigating the exciting world of technology. With a remarkable journey of 7+ years, I have embarked on every step of the **software lifecycle**, from inception to the maintenance of state-of-the-art applications and personalized solutions. My exceptional **analytical abilities**, **problem-solving** finesse, and **out-of-the-box** thinking makes me an asset. I possess excellent **communication skills**, both written and verbal, enabling me to convey ideas effectively.

#### **Education**

**Master of Science - Computer Science** 

GPA:3.7/4

August 2021- May 2023

University of Texas at Arlington. **Courses**: Software Testing, Distributed Systems, Software Design Patterns, Machine Learning, Design Analysis of Algorithms. **Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology** GPA:3.2/4 August 2016 - June 2020

University of Mumbai. Courses: Cryptography Network Security, IoT, Cloud Computing, Database Systems, Microcontroller & Embedded Programming.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages & Web Technologies: Java, Python, JavaScript, Angular 11, JSP, JSON, ¡Query, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, React JS.
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, SQLite, PostgreSQL.
- Frameworks & Tools: Spring, Hibernate, Spring Boot, REST, Micro Services, Jenkins, Maven, Docker, Kubernetes, JUnit, Mockito, GitHub, GitLab.
- Platform & Methodologies: Tomcat, Lambda, Kanban, Apache Kafka, Eclipse, MySQL Workbench, TOAD, Apigee, Swagger, Agile, Scrum, Jira.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Graduate Research Assistant, University of Texas, Arlington, United States

April 2023-Present

- Actively participated in regular **research** meetings and discussions with Dr. Noor, providing progress updates and valuable suggestions for improving translation techniques for array-based loop programs using **Java** and **Scala**.
- Conducted **comprehensive** literature reviews to stay updated with the latest advancements in the field, **enhancing** research outcomes and accuracy while collaborating seamlessly with an interdisciplinary team to design and deploy scalable big data solutions on **Databricks**, ensuring accuracy, and **productivity**.
- Spearheaded the development of pioneering algorithms and methodologies to maximize workflow enhancement by 20% and optimize data processing and storage, resulting in improved performance including Hadoop, Spark, and NoSQL databases, to handle massive data volumes with seamless execution.

# Software Engineer, Reach and Teach Learning Solutions, Mumbai, India

July 2020-August 2021

- Implemented a critical **client-facing RIA** web application using **React Js**, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3. Delivered an exceptional user experience by leveraging **responsive design** principles and ensuring cross-browser compatibility for the ICI Website, resulting in a **20% faster** website and a **30% reduction** in crashes.
- Developed robust **RESTful** web services utilizing **JSON** and **XML** for seamless integration with internal and external systems. Successfully designed and implemented **APIs** that facilitated data exchange and **improved** overall system interoperability.
- Played a crucial role in implementing Continuous Integration practices using Jenkins, GitLab, SonarQube, and Git. Automated build, testing, and deployment processes, resulting in increased development efficiency and reduced time-to-market for software releases.
- Cooperated with senior engineers and management to optimize the website design and Microservices, increasing user satisfaction by 15%.
- Performed enhancements and bug fixes for the website, resulting in a 25% improvement in website stability and a 40% reduction in bugs.

#### Software Engineer Intern, Webstag Technologies, Mumbai, India

January 2019-June 2019

- Streamlined web applications, utilizing technologies such as **Spring IOC** for dependency injection and **Swagger** for API documentation and testing resulting in a **30%** reduction in business process time.
- Created RESTful services using Spring REST for CRUD operations and constructed reusable front-end structures that interacted with these services, enabling 100+ real-time customer data.
- Employed monitoring tools such as EC2, Lambda, and Log4J to analyze logs and performance metrics, identifying areas for improvement and proactive issue resolution.
- Implemented **robust** data storage and **retrieval** solutions using AWS services such as **Amazon RDS** and **DynamoDB**, ensuring data integrity, scalability, and efficient query performance for the application's backend, resulting in seamless user experiences.

## **Projects**

#### Mercado Escolar Application

#### github.com/glencorrreia/MercadoApplication

August 2022-December 2022

- Enhanced the functionality of a full-stack web application by 100+ users using PHP and MySQL for the backend, and ReactJS for the UI.
- Improved an impressive API hit ratio of 94%, ensuring smooth functionality of the application for users.
- Analyzed modern Event Driven Architecture, improved application performance by 80%, and hosted the application on UTA Cloud-Azure.

## Serve Me System (SMS) Application

# github.com/glencorrreia/ServeMeAndroid

May 2022-August 2022

- Developed an Android application to enable 1000+ users to request service efficiently using Java programming and ASP.NET API calls.
- Followed the 7 steps of **Waterfall methodology** to plan and execute the project, ensuring a **test-driven** deployment practice.
- Generated an impressive efficiency rate of 80% in implementing the API calls, ensuring the smooth and seamless functioning of the app.

## Street Child Lost and Found System

# github.com/glencorrreia/StreetChild

January 2020-May 2020

- Researched and developed a web-based application to identify missing children with an impressive accuracy rate of 94% using advanced machine learning techniques such as Logistic Regression and Facial Recognition with an accuracy rate of 99%.
- Authenticated cutting-edge technologies such as React JS, PHP, JavaScript, and Python to develop a user-friendly and intuitive interface.